Okay, so here is our picture of our court counter app, or
这里是我们计数器应用的图片
at least how we want it to look.
至少我们希望它是这个样子
Now, I'm going to follow my own advice and start with the XML first.
现在 我会按照自己的想法 先从 XML 开始
Let's think about the view situation right now.
先想一下现在 View 的情况
So, we still have all these views, and these views are in vertical and
我们有所有 View 垂直排列
linear layouts.
且是 LinearLayout
We have a linear layout for team B and a linear layout for team A.
Team A和 Team B 分别有一个 LinearLayout
and you can't just have two root views so furthermore,
我们不能有两个根 View
these are wrapped in a linear layout, which happens to be horizontal so
它们被包含在一个水平的 LinearLayout里
that these two child linear layouts can be next to one another.
也就是这两个紧邻的垂直 LinearLayout
Okay, now we want to add a reset button down here.
现在我们想在这添加一个 RESET 按钮
For the sake of your brain not exploding thinking about all these
你的大脑先不要考虑这些不同的 LinearLayout
different layouts, I want you to think of everything inside of this
我想让你思考水平 LinearLayout 里边的所有内容
horizontal linear layout kind of like a single view.
这是一种单独的视图
And now you're just trying to lay out this horizontal linear layout right here
现在你要尝试在这布置水平 LinearLayout
and this reset button.
和这个 RESET 按钮
You're trying to lay out two views.
你要尝试布置两个View
One view is at the top and the other view is at the bottom of the screen.
一个是在顶部 另一个在屏幕的底部
So the question now is what view group would allow you to have
所以问题是哪种 ViewGroup 允许你
a view up here at the top and a view down by the bottom of the screen?
将一个 View 放在顶部而另一个 View 放在屏幕的底部呢？
And it turns out that a relative layout is a pretty good candidate for this.
事实证明 LinearLayout 是一个非常好的选择
I can have my horizontal linear layout here, match the parent for
我可以将水平 LinearLayout 放在这 与父 View 的宽度一致
the width, and then wrap content for the height.
把高度设为 wrap_content
And I can have my reset button right here, align with the center and
把 RESET 按钮放在这 居中
bottom of the pairing.
紧贴着底部
Okay, so you have a Relative Layout, and
这样你就有了一个 LinearLayout
that Relative Layout has a Button child and a Linear Layout child.
这个 LinearLayout 有一个按钮和子 LinearLayout
And the Button child is this Reset button, and
按钮是 RESET 按钮
the Linear Layout is the Linear Layout here, the horizontal one.
LinearLayout 就是指我们这里的水平 LinearLayout
Furthermore, this horizontal linear layout has two children, and
而且 这个水平 LinearLayout 有两个子布局
those children are also linear layouts.
这些子布局也是 LinearLayout
They are the linear layout for team A and the linear layout for
你可以看到一个是 Team A 的线性布局
team B that you see here.
一个是Team B 的线性布局
The linear layout for team A has two text views and three buttons.
Team A 的线性布局有两个 TextView 和 三个按钮
The same is true of this linear layout for team B.
Team B 的布局也是一样
Five children, two text views, and three buttons.
有五部分 两个 TextView 和三个按钮
This portion of the layout you've already made,
你已经完成了布局这一部分
you just need to add this, all right, let's do it.
你需要添加这些 好了 我们开始
Okay, I'm here in my XML code and so the first thing I'm going to do is is I'm
来到 XML 代码界面 我将要做的第一件事就是
going to make the Root Relative Layout that you saw in the diagram.
实现根 LinearLayout 你可以在图中看到
So here going to type RelativeLayout, and I actually want
这里应该是 RelativeLayout 我想做的是
to cut and paste these two lines because they need to be in the root layout.
剪切然后粘贴这两行 因为它们需要在根 View 里
So I'm cutting them and I'm pasting them here, in my root layout.
我正在对它们进行剪切 然后粘贴在这 在我的根 View 里
Okay, now I'm going to close off my RelativeLayout here and
关闭这里的 RelativeLayout
I'm going to move this closing tag all the way to the bottom.
把结束标签移动到最尾端
Okay, so what I essentially have right now Is this part of the diagram.
现在我们基本有了图示的东西
All right, looks like I have some errors as well.
好了 看一下有一些错误
Let's see, yes, I haven't defined a height or a width, so let's do that.
这里 我没有设置宽度和高度 我们做这部分
Now my relative layout had the button at the bottom center of the screen.
我的 RelativeLayout 在屏幕的底部中间有一个按钮
So, to do that, it's probably going to need to fill the whole screen.
为了实现它 相对布局需要填充整个屏幕
So I'm going to do match parents on both.
因此将宽度和高度都设置成 match_parents
Okay, now I need to add the button.
现在我需要添加按钮
I'm going to scroll down, right here, to where the linear layout closes,
向下滚动 在这 也就是 LinearLayout 的结束位置
but I still am inside the relative layout, and I'm going to add a button.
但是仍然在 RelativeLayout 里面 添加按钮
And I'm going to go ahead and wrap content for that button,
继续 按钮的宽和高设置成 wrap_content
because it's not a button that expands to fill the entire bottom of
因为它不是一个扩展到整个屏幕底端
the screen or expands to fill the entire screen.
或者整个屏幕的按钮
And now the parent of this button is the RelativeLayout, and
按钮的父 View 是 RelativeLayout
we're going to set the text of this button to Reset.
我们将按钮的文本设置为 Reset
Let's see what this looks like.
我们看一下它是什么样子
Okay so my reset button's up here, that's not exactly where I want it to
RESET 按钮在这 却不是我们想要的位置
be, but it's parent is relatively out, that fills up the entire screen.
它的父 View 是填充整个屏幕的 RelativeLayout
So I can align it to the parent.
我可以将它对准父 View
I want to align it to the parents bottom, and
让它贴紧父 View 的底部
I want it to be in the center of the parent, horizontally anyways.
我想让它在父 View 的中央 并且水平
Cool, my button seems to be in the right place.
按钮已经在正确的位置了
I'm going to select everything here.
将这里的代码全选
And I'm going to do a command option L on Mac.
在 Mac 上点击 command + L
Which is the same thing as Control-Alt-L on Windows to just reformat the code and
或者在 Windows 使用 Control+Alt+L 来重新排列代码
get it to look nice.
看起来更好了
Okay let's go back to our Java code.
我们回到 Java 代码
Now I've got my button but it's not doing anything.
现在我们虽然有了代码 但是还没有实现功能
Let's start by making a method for it.
从给它添加方法开始
I'm going to make this right above the display methods, here, public void.
在 display 方法前添加方法 public void
I'm going to call this method resetScore,
我把方法叫做 resetScore
because that's what I intend for it to do.
因为这就是我想让它做的
Scroll up, I'm going to make it match these other methods
向上滚动 让它和其他方法匹配
with the View v, and then, curly braces.
View v 然后是大括号
I won't worry about what's going to go in here for now.
先不要担心这里是什么
I'm going to go back to my XML code And
回到 XML 代码
I'm going to do the second part of the hooking the button to the Java code
我要做的第二部分是将按钮和 Java 代码绑定
by adding a onClick attribute here for resetScore.
通过给 resetScore 添加 onClick 属性
Okay, so now when I click this button the code here will be run, but
当我点击这个按钮的时候 代码会运行
there isn't any code here.
而不是其他代码
Let's figure out what I need to add.
我们需要添加些什么
Okay, let's go back to this discussion of pseudoCode.
我们回到伪代码的讨论
When I hit the Reset button, what do I want to happen?
当我点击 RESET 按钮 会发生什么呢？
Well, I want both of these two scores to show 0.
我想让这两个分数都显示0
Furthermore, I want the variables for score team A and for
就是说 Team A 和 Team B 的变量的值
score team B to go back to zero.
都变成 0
Remember, when I click on any of these buttons, I'm adding two and
记住 当我点击这些按钮中的任何一个时 会给
then displaying the variable.
变量加2并且显示出来
So, if I don't put the variable back to zero,
所以 如果我不使变量归零的话
it's going to show an incorrect number.
它就会显示一个错误的数字
So here’s what I came up with pseudoCode-wise.
所以我们需要的是
The first thing I want to do is set the score for Team A to zero.
第一件事就是我想把 Team A 的分数设置为 0
Then I want to do the same thing for Team B.
然后对 Team B 做同样的事
Now both of the scores are zero, but nothing's been displayed yet, which is
现在两队的分数都为 0 但是没有什么显示出来
why in Step 3 I'll display the score for Team A, which has been set to zero.
这就是为什么要有第三步 即显示已经设置为0的Team A 的分数
And to be a little bit more specific, I’m going to display the score for
I鈥檓 going to display the score for 说的更具体一点 就是在这显示
Team A here, and then I'll display the score for Team B here.
Team A 的分数 在这显示Team B 的分数
And because in Steps 1 and 2, I've ensured that they're set to zero,
因为第一步和第二步 我确定它们已经被设置为0
they will display zero here and here.
它们会在这和这显示0
Then when I click any of these buttons to update ScoreForTeamA or
当我点击这些按钮中的任何一个来给 ScoreForTeamA 或
ScoreForTeamB, it's going to be updating but starting with a score of zero.
ScoreForTeamB 增加分数时 它会从0开始增加
Okay, so in reset score I'm going to type my pseudo code as code, code.
在重置分数时 我要把伪代码写成代码
So the first thing I'm going to do is take score A and set it's value to
第一步 使用0和赋值符将A 的分数
zero using a assignment operator here and the value of zero.
设置为0
Oh and don't forget the semi colon of course.
别忘了分号
I'll do the same for score B.
对于 B 做相同的事情
After that, I'm going to display in the team A spot, the score for team A.
之后 在 Team A 的区域显示 Team A 的分数
And then I'm going to display in the team B spot, the score for team B.
然后在 Team B 的区域显示 Team B 的分数
I'll also go ahead here and add a comment.
继续然后在这添加一个注释
Okay, this all seems reasonable.
这些看起来很合理
And it's been a while since I've run anything on my phone, so
因为我的手机上运行的是先前没有改动的
I'm going to press the Run button, okay, cool.
所以我需要重新运行
I have a RESET button.
我有一个 RESET 按钮
Let's see if it works.
看一下它是否工作
Good, it sets to zero.
很好 它重置为0了
Let's click a little bit more,
我们再点多一些数字
just to make sure that everything's still working.
确保所有的东西都正常运行
Cool, and it looks like it is, awesome.
正常运行 真棒
Now this was a little bit of a tricky one.
现在有一个有点复杂的问题
So let me show you what happens if you were to switch around the order,
我给你展示一下 如果你调换代码的位置会发生什么
do something a little bit differently.
做一些不同的东西
What if I switch these two around?
我调换这两个会怎样呢？
Well, let's just see what happens.
我们看一下发生了什么
Okay, so here it is, let's see what it does.
我们看到它成功运行
Okay, so I'm going to add some points.
我会添加一些分数
Now for the moment of truth, Reset button.
现在点击 RESET 按钮
Huh, doesn't seem to do anything.
它好像没有做任何事
Let's try clicking, huh, interesting.
再点击试试 有趣
Well it's kind of hard to see,
看起来一点难度
but the score before said 19, I hit the reset button nothing changed.
在分数显示19之前 我点击了 RESET 按钮 但是没什么改变
But then when I hit free throw it showed one.
但是当我点击 FREE THROW 时 它显示1
let's try with the other side, if I hit plus two points.
尝试另一边 如果我点击 +2 POINTS
Oh, it shows two.
它显示2
let's look at the code again for why that might be the case.
我们再看一看代码 为什么会这样
So I switched around displaying and setting the score.
因为我调换了显示和设置分数的代码
Just to see what kind of error behavior I might get from that.
看一下它会发生什么错误呢？
Let's say TeamA has a score of 30 and TeamB has a score of 40.
比如 Team A 有30分 Team B 有40分
When I say displayForTeamA it's going to show 30 and
当我执行 displayForTeamA 它会显示30
when I say displayForTeamB it's going to show 40.
当我执行 displayForTeamB 它会显示40
Only after that, will it actually set these values to zero.
在那之后 它才会设置它们的值为0
But since it displayed first it's not going to show the values of zero.
但是显示的数字却不会是0
But the variable will be zero.
但是实际上它们的变量已经是0
So when I press something like addThreeForTeamB, it's going to take
所以当我们点击 addThreeForTeamB 时 它会读取设置的分数变量
the value of zero that I set down here, add three, and then display three.
然后加3并显示出来
So to us, it would look like TeamB went from having a score of 30 then to
对我们来说 就像 Team B 原来是30分
after clicking the reset button, a score of three, which is kind of a weird jump.
但是点击 RESET 按钮后 就变成了3分 这是一种怪异的跳跃
Now one way I could fix this besides swapping it back to how it should be
现在不换回它们的位置而修复错误的一个方式是
Is I could put display zero here.
在这里显示0分
And you can test this out on your own, but this would actually work.
你可以在你自己的设备上测试 但是它确实能够运行
It's just a little bit counterintuitive.
只是有点麻烦
I like showing examples like this because it kind of shows the beauty and
我喜欢展示这样的例子 因为它的代码
subjectivity of code.
简洁 美观
Now, in this case, I happen to think fairly strongly that the first way that
在这个例子里 我认为我第一次写代码的方式
I had the code was better.
更好
But you might start seeing scenarios where there could be two different
但是你会看到在这种情况下 可以有两种不同的
ways to write the code, and both of them are technically correct.
方式来写代码 这两种方式在技术上都是正确的
Since there isn't always one right answer,
因为没有唯一的答案
you shouldn't feel constricted to do it the exact correct way.
你不应该被正确的方式所局限
Try coding up something that works your way, see how other people do it,
尝试用自己的方式实现 再看看别人是怎么做的
and then compare, who's more efficient, whose code is clearer.
然后比较 谁的方式更高效 谁的代码更简洁
These kind of discussions could be a really helpful learning experience.
这种讨论能成为非常有帮助的学习经验
Okay, but I'm going to revert the code back to the state that it was before
把代码调整回之前运行正确的状态
which was working and
能正常运行
now I have all the functionality of my app but it's not pretty, let's fix that.
现在我的应用的功能已经有了 但是它还不够美观 我们修改一下